Ayush Sharma

Personal website: https://ayushsharma.dev/

Email: ayushs217@gmail.com Telephone: +1 (678)-330-0438

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern – Northrop Grumman (05/2020 – Present)

- Developed a Microsoft PowerApp for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Public Health Department which handles automated testing with PowerBl, PowerAutomate and Python.
- Lead a team of 3 interns to design a second PowerApp for the CDC Project Research Center to allow users to add research projects for the Department of Non-Infectious Diseases.
- Improved and updated UI for multiple CDC Administrator Apps.
- Used REST API, Java Script and Socrata to automate facts sheets for all US States to be used by the Office on Smoking & Health.

STEM Mentor – Georgia Institute of Technology (09/2019 – Present)

- Employed at CEISMC (Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics and Computing) at Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Taught High School sophomore & juniors about STEM at the Davis Charter Senior Academy & Henry W. Grady High School.
- Worked with Horizons and K.I.D.S/STEAM program at Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Teaching elementary and middle school kids about the wonders of STEM.

Chief Executive Officer – 4 Years LLC (05/2018 – Present)

- 4 Years was created in order to help international and domestic students get into top US Universities. All services, such as the ASD, are free of charge.
- Lead developer of 4 Years website and Accepted Student Database.
- Designed and implemented a customer and employee login system of 75 users by provisioning Google Firebase and Cloud Firestore.
- Manages ACT Tutoring team of 20 and website development team of 5.
- Partnered with Microsoft to sponsor a free college exposition panel event on November 27th, 2019.

EDUCATION

Georgia State University Honors College (2019 – 2023)

- Member of the Computer Science Club & Panther Hackers.
- Dean's List (Fall 2020 & Spring 2021)

Alpharetta High School (2015 – 2019)

Graduated with Honors and ended with a 3.94 GPA.

ABOUT ME

Freshman Undergraduate
Computer Science major from
Georgia State University (3.86
GPA) with experience in various
fields of technology and
engineering such as iOS &
Android app development,
Amazon Web Services (AWS),
HTML/CSS, Java, and Python

I have had the pleasure to work for technology conglomerates, universities and 501c (3) non-profit organizations such as Lockheed Martin, Microsoft, Georgia Institute of Technology, North American Thrombosis Forum, International Rescue Committee, Pennies for Patients and the Red Cross.

Industrious, diligent and fast learning student with 4+ years of experience in a technology real-world environment.

Soft Skills: Adaptability, Fast-Learner, Problem Solving, Project
Management and Leadership

Programming: Python, Java, HTML,SwiftUI, Firebase,Cloud Firestore, PowerApps and React Native.